（大門カイト）ルーク　お前…。
Rook! No way!
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
そうだよ。　オルペウスが僕のために→
Yes way! Orpheus gave me an Armlet once again!
再び　腕輪を授けてくれたんだ。
オルペウスが!?
Orpheus did?!
（ルーク）僕は決めた。　オルペウスの
理想のために　この身をささげる。
I've made up my mind.
I'll devote myself to making Orpheus's utopia a reality.
神のパズルを解き
僕が　ファイ・ブレインになる！→
I'll solve the Puzzle of God and become the Phi Brain!
彼の見た未来は　絶対だ。→
The future he foresaw is unchangeable.
There isn't anything or anyone who can escape that fate.
何者も　その運命からは
逃れる事はできない。
くっ…　ふざけんじゃねえ！
Kiss my ass!
I'm not gonna let some ancient prick decide my future!
俺の未来は　オルペウスなんかに
決めさせねえ！
そんな運命
何度だって変えてやる！
I'm gonna rewrite that fate as many times as I have to!
The same goes for you, Rook!
ルーク　お前もだ。　俺は何度だって
お前を救ってみせる！
I'm gonna save you as many times as I have to!
やっぱり　カイトは　すごいや。
Kaito, you're really amazing.
This way, I can become an eternity for you.
これで僕は　君の永遠になれる。
くっ…　ルーク!!
Rook!
ここは…　うっ！
Where am I?
I have the brain of a god.
私は　神の頭脳を持つ者…
ファイ・ブレインの　オルペウス。
I am the Phi Brain, Orpheus.
I will surpass the gods.
私が神を超える…。
くだらねえもん見せやがって…。
Stop showing me your bullshit!
ルーク　お前の遺志は
絶対　無駄にしねえ！
Rook, I'm not letting your death be in vain.
But then what about Rook?
（フリーセル）
そ…　それじゃあ　ルークは…。
（真方ジン）死んだよ。
それが　大門カイトの出した答えだ。
He died.
That was Daimon Kaito's answer.
（逆之上ギャモン）
でたらめ　ぬかしてんじゃねえぞ！
Don't give us that crap! He'd never go down that way!
あいつが　んなまね
するわけねえじゃねえか！
信じないのなら　それでも構わん。
It's up to you to believe me or not.
However, it's a fact that Rook is dead.
だが　ルークが敗れたのは事実だ。
私が見たとおりにな。
Just the way I foresaw it too.
Stop your pointless struggle and aim for even further heights.
（ジン）くだらぬ感傷を捨て
更なる高みを目指せ。→
Beat Daimon Kaito and become the Phi Brain.
大門カイトを倒し
ファイ・ブレインとなるのだ。
What do you think?
どう思う？
ルークに限って…。
信じたくはないけれど…。
I don't want to believe that about Rook.
チッ。　フリーセル
お前は　どうするつもりだ？
Freecell, what are you going to do?
I'll settle things with Kaito.
俺は　カイトと決着をつける。
それが　俺の役目だからな。
That's my role.
まさか　君は…。
Are you serious?
The two to challenge the Puzzle of God will be decided here.
（エニグマ）ここで　神のパズルに挑む
２人が決まるんだ。→
I can see you again soon, my dear Lovushka.
もうすぐ　君に会えるね
僕のラヴーシュカ。
Kaito, there's something we want to ask you.
（フリーセル）
カイト　聞きたい事があるんだ。
ルークの事なんだけど。
It's about Rook.
お前たちには関係ねえ。
It's got nothing to do with you.
ギャモン　フリーセル
お前たちは　もう　パズルを解くな。
Gammon, Freecell... Stop solving his puzzles.
パズルを解くのは　この俺だ。
I'll solve his puzzles.
お前たちは　ここから帰れ。
Get out of here.
You're just too kind, Kaito.
君は優しすぎるよ　カイト。
Seems Orpheus was telling the truth.
どうやら　オルペウスの言っていた事は
本当らしいな。→
「パズルを解くな」だ？　寝ぼけた事
ぬかしてんじゃねえ！
You? Solving puzzles? Give me a break.
ムカつくぜ。
You piss me off.
The way you are now you'll just let Rook's death be in vain.
てめえが　そんなんじゃ
ルークも　うかばれねえ！→
Get lost.
てめえこそ　どっかへ消えな。
（姫川エレナ）あっ　見えた。
I found it!
（井藤ノノハ）
ん？　あの小さく見えるやつ？
そうそう。
It's that tiny thing on the horizon?
Yeah.
エニグマも　オルペウスも　卑怯なまねしたら
許さないんだから。
Enigma and Orpheus will have to pay if they pull something nasty.
でも　人払いしてるって事は→
Judging by the remote location they called the boys to, they must be scheming something.
やっぱり
何か　たくらんでるのかも…。
Don't worry.
心配　要らないわよ。
え？
They've solved impossibly difficult puzzles before.
どんなに難しいパズルでも
あいつらは解いてきたじゃない。
今度だって　きっと大丈夫よ。
信じて待ちましょ。
They'll be fine this time too.
We should believe in them and wait.
I know.
分かってる。　分かってるけど
何だか胸騒ぎがして…。
I know, but something about it is unsettling.
（エレナ）気合いよ～！　ギャモーン！
Good luck, Gammon!
ルーク様　ファイトー！
Beat them, Sir Rook!
W-What are you doing all of a sudden?
と…　突然　何!?
応援よ　応援。→
Just cheering for them.
ついでに…　レイツェルも頑張れ～！
Also...
Raetsel, don't give up!
Kaito! Freecell! Don't you dare lose!
カイト！　フリーセル君！　負けるな～！
You can do it, Gammon!
（エレナ）ギャモーン！　頑張れ～！
Guys! Good luck!
みんな～！　頑張れ～！
（エニグマ）
ようこそ　ファイ・ブレインの子供たち。
Welcome, children of the Phi Brain.
Now we only need to wait for Raetsel.
（エニグマ）
あとは　レイツェルを待つばかりだね。
そんな必要は　ねえ！
No, we don't!
（モニター）「どっかで見てんだろ!?
オルペウス！→
I know you're watching, Orpheus!
Stop screwing around!
回りくどいまねする事はねえ。
さっさと俺を器にしろ！」。
Take me for your vessel already!
エニグマ！
お前の目的は分かってんだ！
Enigma! I know what you want!
I'll be sure to handle it all!
この俺が　全部　引き受けてやる！
Stop making us just through pointless hoops!
だから　もう
こんな茶番は終わりにしろ！
悪いが　それは　できない相談だ。
Too bad. That's out of question.
大門カイト！
お前が親友を失ったのは→
Daimon Kaito, you lost your best friend because you're not yet suited to serve as a vessel.
まだ　その器ではないからだ。
何!?
What?
If you were ready to serve as a vessel, you could've easily saved Rook.
本当に　器として完成していれば→
ルークの命など
たやすく救えたはずだがねぇ。
（モニター・エニグマ）
「まずは　パズルを解きたまえ。
話は　それからだ」。
Solve the puzzles first.
We can talk after that.
Did it! Found them!
（ピノクル）やった！　見つけた！
（軸川ソウジ）よかった
カイト君たちは無事みたいだ。
Phew! They all seem to be in one piece!
（アナ・グラム）ピノピノ　お疲れ～。
Good job, Pinopino!
Peeking isn't a nice thing to do.
（モニター・エニグマ）
「のぞき見とは　趣味が悪い。→
We'd have told you if you just asked. The two to challenge the Puzzle of Gods will be decided here.
そんなまねをしなくても
教えてあげよう。→
これから　神のパズルに挑戦する
２人を決めるところだ。→
チョロチョロと動き回っているようだが
無駄だよ。→
Apparently, you've been sniffing around, but it's pointless.
Orpheus can see through all your petty schemes.
オルペウスには　全て　お見通しさ。
フッフッハ…」。
あっ！
それは…。
オルペウスの腕輪！
What?!
An Orpheus Armlet?!
ジンを見てきた　お前なら
それが　どんなもんか分かるだろ!?
Didn't you see what that did to Jin? You should know what it's capable of!
Yeah, I do. I'll use the Armlet to become the Phi Brain.
もちろんよ。　この腕輪を使って
私が　ファイ・ブレインになる。
ジンを救うのは　私よ。
I'm going to be the one to save Jin.
レイツェル！
Raetsel...
Now that you're all here,
（エニグマ）
さて…　これで全員そろったね。
move to your lifts.
では　それぞれのリフトへ
移動してもらおう。
Kaito!
（ギャモン）カイト！→
俺は　この勝負
一歩も引くつもりはねえ！
I'm gonna go all-out in this battle!
たとえ
お前が死ぬ事になってもな！
Even if that means you bite the dust!
てめえには　あんのか？
Are you determined to stop at nothing to solve the Puzzle of God?
どんな手を使っても
神のパズルを解く覚悟が！
俺は…。
俺は　誰も死んでほしくねえ。
I just don't want to let anyone die anymore.
ただ　それだけだ！
That's all.
待ちやがれ！　おい…　くそっ。
Stop! Hey!
Dammit.
これから　君たちが行うのは
対戦型のバトルロイヤルだ。→
You will be fighting in a battle royal here.
You must move the blocks in your way, and reach the goal.
フィールド内の　行く手を塞ぐブロックを
動かし　ゴールを目指せ。→
ブロック表面に出現する
アイコンに触れれば→
By touching the icons showing up on the sides of the blocks,
you can make the blocks move.
その方向に移動する。→
動いたブロックは
すぐに戻す事はできない。→
Blocks can't be returned right after they were moved once.
There are two one-person escape pods in the center of the field.
中央のゴールには　１人乗りの
脱出カプセルを２つ用意した。
The two winners will get to challenge the Puzzle of God.
勝者には
神のパズルへの道が開かれる。
On the other hand, those who fail will face severe punishment.
だが　敗れた者には
厳しい罰を受けてもらう。
Cubik, what's your progress?
キュービック君　進捗は　どう？
（キュービック・Ｇ）
うん　あと一息だよ。
It's going well. Just a little more.
Destroy. Orpheus system. Proceeding to final phase.
（イワシミズ君）デストロイ　オルペウスシステム
最終フェーズに移行…。
だっ!?
あっ　ごめん。
Ah, sorry.
イワリン　かっちょいい！
Iwarin so cool-a-go-go!
これで
フリーセルたちが救えるんだね。
We can save Freecell and the others now, right?
Yeah. If the Order's ancient scriptures are right,
ああ。　オーダーの古文書が真実なら→
we must aim for the moment Orpheus takes over the new host.
オルペウスが　ターゲットを乗っ取る
瞬間をたたけば…。
（イワシミズ君）警告する。→
Warning. The chance of success for this mission is approximately 0.001.
このミッションの成功確率は
０．００１。　０．００１。
危険なのは分かってるよ
イワシミズ君。
We know it's dangerous, Iwashimizu.
確かに　状況は　かなり厳しい。
Yeah, the conditions aren't exactly in our favor.
でも　僕たちは
その僅かな可能性に→
But we've got no choice but to bet on what slim chance we have.
賭けてみるしかないんだ。
（ピノクル　アナ）うん。
了解。　了解。　了解。
Roger. Roger.
You wanna see Raerae too, right?
ね…。　レイレイに会いたいね。
アナは　レイレイの事　とっても心配。
I'm really worried about her.
Now then... Puzzle time start!
それでは　パズルタイム　スタート！
ふざけやがって…　何が「罰」だ！
Who do they think they are? Punishment?!
どんなに
回りくどい仕掛けをしようが→
I don't care how many hoops I've gotta jump through first!
オルペウスと決着をつけるのは
この俺だ！
I'll be the one to settle the score with Orpheus!
We can't see each other, so we need to predict each other's positions.
心の声
（ギャモン）姿の見えねえ相手の
位置を予測する方法は　２つ。→
一つは　ブロックの位置。
もう一つは…。
One hint for that is the position of the blocks.
The other is...
（ブロックの移動する音）
心の声
（ギャモン）この音だ。→
this sound.
逆に　こいつを利用すりゃ→
Using these, we can screw each other too.
Are we now trying to trick each other?
相手を　かく乱する事も
できるってわけか…。→
Not gonna lose in that!
だまし合いなら負けねえぞ。
Jin, you're still on a long and difficult journey.
心の声
（レイツェル）ジン　あなたは　まだ
長く　つらい旅を続けてる…。
心の声
（レイツェル）あなたとの
思い出さえあれば→
As long as I have my memories of you, nothing can scare me.
私は…　何も怖くない。
心の声
（レイツェル）待ってて…
もうすぐ　私が助けてあげるから。
Wait for me. I'll be there right away to save you.
Kaito, Raetsel... Where are you?
心の声
（フリーセル）カイト　レイツェル
一体　どこにいるんだ…。→
I'll move this block next.
次に動かす　ブロックは…。
Why do I have this bad premonition?
何だろう…　嫌な予感がする。
でも　この先にしか勝機はない！
But this is the only way I can win!
（ブロックの移動する音）
見えた。
Got you.
（フリーセル）しまった！
Dammit!
フフフッ。　私の勝ちね。
I win!
そうはさせるか！
Not gonna let you!
誰だ!?
Who was that?
Raetsel.
レイツェルだ…。
気付いた時には遅かったよ。
By the time I realized, it was too late.
Wonderful. So only one seat left.
まじぃな。　残る席は　あと１つか。
Huh?
（ギャモン）マジか!?
You've gotta be shitting me!
あっ!?　まさか…。
No way!
Thanks!
これ　ありがとう。
えっ？　あ…　ちょっと！
Hey!
ギャモーン！　フリーセル！　大丈夫か!?
Gammon!
Freecell!
Are you okay?
ああ！　僕は大丈夫だ！
Yeah! I'm fine!
ギャモーン！　どうした!?
Gammon! What happened?
Answer!
おい　返事しろ！
うっせえ！　聞こえてんだよ！
Shut yer trap!
I can hear you!
くっ…　しくじったぜ。
I screwed up.
Let's give them one more push.
さ～て　もう一息だ。→
やつらを
もっともっと追い込んで→
We need to corner them as much as possible,
確実に　ファイ・ブレインに
なってもらわなければ。
so that they can become the Phi Brain
僕たちの幸せな未来のために…。
for the sake of our beautiful future.
ギャモン！　フリーセル！　俺に任せてくれ。
Gammon! Freecell!
Leave this to me! I'll find a way that we can all get out safe and sound!
みんなが無事に脱出できる方法を
絶対に見つけ出してやる！
フッ…。　てめえみたいな
中途半端な野郎は黙ってろ！
You're a half-assed loser! Stop acting so high and mighty!
What?
（ギャモン）うっ…　邪魔すんな。
このパズルは　俺が解く…。→
Don't get in my way. I'll solve this puzzle.
I'm gonna crush Orpheus.
そして…　オルペウスをぶっ潰すのは
この逆之上ギャモン様だ！
I, the great Sakanoue Gammon!
くっ…。
（フリーセル）決めたよ　カイト。
I've made up my mind, Kaito!
僕も同じだ！
ここで決着をつけよう！
I feel the same way too!
Let's settle this here and now!
This isn't the time or place for that!
そんな事
言ってる場合じゃねえだろうが！
ガタガタうるせえぞ！　うぐっ…。
Oh shut the fuck up already!
パズルタイムを続けるぜ。
Puzzle time's not over yet!
Don't you get it?
何で分かんねえ!?
このパズルは違うんだ！
This puzzle's different!
冷徹で
ためらいってもんが　ねえ。
It's cold and doesn't have even a hint of hesitation.
One of us still needs to solve it.
だとしても　誰かが
このパズルを解かなきゃならない。
This is Orpheus's final test puzzle.
これは　オルペウスの出した
最後の試練のパズルだからね。
最後の試練？
The final test?
That's right. He's testing us.
そう。　僕たちを試しているんだ。
誰かを犠牲にしてでも
パズルを解く覚悟があるか。
He's testing our determination to solve puzzles even if it means that someone else will die.
んな事　関係ねえ！
Who cares about that?
I'm getting out of here alive.
俺は生きて　ここを出る。
お前や　ギャモンと一緒にな！
Together with you and Gammon!
フッ…
やっぱり　カイトは優しすぎるよ。
You're really too kind, Kaito.
それなら
君の好きなようにすればいい！
Then just do whatever you want.
うぅ…。　白黒　はっきり
つけようじゃねえか！
We're gonna settle things without any doubt here!
うわっ！→
くっ…　閉じ込められた!?
I've been locked in!
I can't move on from here.
もはや　逆転の手はない。
ここまでか…。
This is it, huh?
カイト…　君のおかげで　僕は
また　パズルを好きになれた。
Kaito, thanks to you, I started to like puzzles again.
回想
解けたら　また次のパズルを
始めりゃいいだけさ。→
Even if we solve this, there are always more puzzles waiting.
Time's already been in motion for you, Freecell.
お前の時間は　とっくに
動きだしてんだぜ　フリーセル。
（フリーセル）僕だけじゃない。
ルークや　ピノクル　ダウト　ミゼルカ…。→
And it's not just me.
Rook and Pinochle, Doubt, Mizerka...
たくさんの　パズラーが
君に救われたんだ。
You've saved so many puzzlers.
That kindness of yours must be what helps you win.
その優しさが　きっと
君の切り札になるはずだ。
心の声
違う…。　これも違う。→
Wrong.
Not this either.
No. No.
これも…　これも！→
これは
俺の探してる答えじゃねえ。
These aren't the solutions I'm looking for.
This doesn't count as solving it at all.
こんなんじゃ
解けた事にはならねえ…。
どこだ？　どこにあるんだ？
Where is it?
Where's the way to save us all?
俺たち全員が助かる方法は！
うぅ…　一歩　遅かったか。
Was I a moment late?
ギャモン　先に行け！
Gammon, go ahead!
What?
けがしてるお前が先だ。
You're hurt. Go ahead.
俺は　フリーセルと　あとから行く！
I'll go later with Freecell.
ハッ！　何が「あとから」だよ。
勝算もねえくせに。
Later, huh? You've got nothing up your sleeve.
うるせえ！
いいから　黙って俺の…。
Shut up! Just shut up and do what I—
ギャモン！
Gammon!
ギャモン　無事か!?
（ギャモン）ああ…　何とかな…。
Gammon, are you all right?!
I'm alive...
待ってろ。　今　助ける！
Just wait! I'll dig you out!
（ギャモン）俺の事は　ほっとけ…。
Just leave me.
There's no solution that you'd like here.
ここには　おめえの探してるような
答えは　ねえ…。
生き残るのは　たった１人…
そういうパズルなんだ。
Only one can survive.
That's how this puzzle is designed.
バカ言うな！
勝手に…　諦めてんじゃねえぞ…。
Give me a break!
Don't give up just yet!
俺は…　誰も死なせねえ！　くっ…。
I'm not letting anyone die!
You just don't know when to give up, do you?
（ギャモン）往生際の悪い野郎だぜ…。→
You've gotta stomach this!
いい加減　腹くくれ！→
You're gonna solve every puzzle, aren't you?
おめえは
全てのパズルを解くんだろ!?→
Solve them, Kaito.
パズルを解け　カイト。→
あの滅亡の未来を
塗り替えられんのは→
You're the only one who can rewrite that future of destruction.
おめえしかいねえ。
ギャモン…。
Gammon...
（フリーセル）カイト！
Kaito!
君は僕に　パズルを解けって
言ってくれたじゃないか。
You told me to solve puzzles.
だから　君が迷うな！
You of all people shouldn't hesitate!
Solve it!
解くんだ…　神のパズルを！
Solve the Puzzle of God!
くっ…　お前たち…。
Guys...
（エニグマ）決まったね。
It's done.
Let it go up in beautiful fireworks.
最後は　派手に締めくくろう。
[無線]（操作音）
うっ…。　くっそ…。
Dammit!
ギャモーン！　フリーセル！
Gammon! Freecell!
行け～！　カイト！
Go, Kaito!
くっ…　行くんだ！　カイト！
You must go, Kaito!
Don't hesitate!
迷うな！
行け～！
Go!
ギャモン。
カイト　フリーセル君。
Gammon...
Kaito... Freecell...
あっ　待って！
Wait!
あっ　ありがとう。
Ah, thanks.
ピノクル君　これは？
ああ…　フリーセルが作った　パズルさ。
What's this, Pinochle?
A puzzle Freecell made.
お気に入りだったから
持っていってあげようと思って。
He liked it a lot, so I thought I should bring it.
I see. It's a good one.
そうか…。　いいパズルだね。
The possible futures are converging.
（ジン）未来は収束しつつある。→
It doesn't matter how hard you struggle,
お前が　いくら　あがこうと
もう何も変えられない。→
you can't change anything anymore.
これで…　全てが　そろった。
Now everything is ready.
The time has come.
ついに　この時が来たんだ…。
Preview
The target is Orpheus. We must plan this carefully.
Leave it to me!